

📕+1 210-609-8772 | 💌 caasilemroh@gmail.com | 😭 isaachormel.com | 🖸 https://github.com/rewrite123 | 🛅 https://www.linkedin.com/in/isaac-hormel/

"It's hard to beat a person who never gives up"

Summary _

Dedicated employee with over three years of professional experience as a fullstack developer specializing in MERN technologies. Lead projects and consulted on teams to ensure overall success on the projects I am responsible for. I have a passion for Linux (Ubuntu), open source software, and hardware tinkering. Interested in devising solutions to challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools as the need arises.

Technologies.

- NodeJS
- TypeScript
- JavaScript
- Git
- Angular
- React
- Webpack
- Rollup

- RxJS
- MaterialUI
- Bootstrap
- Babel
- SASS/SCSS
- HTML/CSS/JS
- ExpressJS
- RESTful API

- Docker
- NGINX
- MySQL
- PostgreSQL
- ElasticSearch
- Prisma
- Sequelize
- TypeORM

- AWS
- Heroku
- Linux (Ubuntu)
- SSH
- Ansible
- Figma

Work Experience ____

ThrivSports

SR. FULLSTACK DEVELOPER & PROJECT LEAD

Sep. 2019 - Sep. 2022 full/part

- Lead backend engineer for new TypeScript API for internal use and for use with partners.
- Consulted on Elastic Search API for fast Map requests and location data.
- Responsible for React CRM portal for coaches and coach managers.
- Project lead for React search marketplace with Google Maps for coach location services.
- Project lead for React coach booking applet. An applet showcasing services coaches offer and their availabilities that are open for purchase.
- Project lead for React coach profile applet. An applet that showed coach bio, certifications, events, and affiliation.

BatRX

LEAD FRONTEND DEVELOPER

Mar. 2020 - Feb. 2021

- Lead frontend developer for React SPA for data entry and submission with the ability to see and sort data with chartJS.
- Consulted on backend APIs and use with Swagger documentation.

Freelance

FULLSTACK, MOBILE, WEB DESIGN

Feb. 2019 - current

- · Lead developer for SportsVet, responsible for all APIs, design files, and mobile React Native views over a two month period.
- Frontend Angular developer for Portland Web Design responsible for creating an maintaining inventory software for a large client.
- Consulted on software implementations and requirements for a hardware startup that collected data in the field and on job sights.
- · Consulted on management of Wordpress websites for a client who had recently aquired a batch of sites without a site manager or developer with prior experience.
- · Consultant for Flask developer who needed assistance with data collection and view management for his business.
- Consulted in the development of platform Symbio for hiring and empowering marginalized groups.
- UX and graphic designer for a variety of companies, especially startups, in the creation of media or design files.

Personal Projects

pdfmason.com

FOUNDER & SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Sep. 2022

- Created APIs in AWS with Docker, TypeScript, and ExpressJS that allowed users to upload pdfs and word documents for conversion or merging together.
- Fully managed the creation of a React SPA in MaterialUI that tracked time spent for each client and provided a detailed preview of all the fields included in the invoice for customization.

FundLabs

FOUNDER & SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Feb. 2022

- A website dedicated to easily generating customer invoices from a personal tool I created for my clients.
- · Created APIs for the customer login, payment, time logging, and invoice pdf generation in TypeScript, ExpressJS, and Docker.
- Created React SPA with Material UI that tracked time spent for each client and provided a detailed preview of all the fields included in the invoice for customization.

StyleLab

FRONTEND DEVELOPER

Oct. 2022

• A component and styling library like Bootstrap or Materialize with the addition of React components built with Rollup and Type-Script.

ESP32 wifi switch

C HARDWARE PROGRAMING

Mar. 2020

- A small ESP32 project to power on and off a power switch over a wifi TCP connection.
- Another smaller project, this time porting over Marauder software with use with the popular hacking tool Flipper to PlatformIO for use on Linux and OSX.

Raspberry Pi Cluster

System Admin

July 2020

- Set up raspberry pi 3 B cluster managed with Kubernetes and Docker.
- · Hosted simple static website with NGINX as a round-robin load balancer and reverse proxy for simple React website and API.

Education

University of Texas at El Paso

El Paso. Tx

COMPUTER SCIENCE

July 2017 - Mar. 2018

 Attended UTEP briefly in pursuit of a computer science degree, but ultimately dropped out in favor of a coding bootcamp and fulltime employment in IT.

University of Texas at Austin Coding Boot Camp

Austin, Tx

COMPUTER SCIENCE

Aug. 2018 - Jan. 2019

- Attended the UTA Coding Boot Camp where I learned about frontend technologies like React and Ember, databases, and backend technologies like ExpressJS and Prisma.
- Finished the course with an overall grade of A-